Harold Fielding, Ltd. Contracts and correspondence for productions of Frank Loesser's Hans Anderson, 1974-1978: Guide.
Harold Fielding, Ltd. Contracts and correspondence for productions of Frank Loesser's Hans Anderson: Guide
1974-1978
Eda Kuhn Loeb Music Library, Harvard College Library
Ms. Coll. 129
1 box
This collection consists of contracts, memorandums, and letters relating to Harold Fielding's stage production of Frank Loesser's musical Hans Anderson which opened in London on December 17, 1974.
Scope and Content
The collection contains contracts that specify terms of engagement and related paperwork, including letters, and memorandum, relating to Harold Fielding's production of Hans Andersen, which opened at the London Palladium on 17 Dec 1974 and ran for 383 performances. A revival opened in London on 17 Dec 1977 and closed on 28 Feb 1978. Includes contracts signed by Alyn Ainsworth, Willougby Goddard, Sally Ann Howes, Milo O'Shea, Albin Pahernik, and Anthony Valentine. The stage musical was based on the 1952 screen musical Hans Christian Andersen, produced by Sam Goldwyn and including music and lyrics by Frank Loesser.
Historical Note
In 1952 lyricist and composer Frank Loesser was hired by film producer Samuel Goldwyn to write the songs for his movie Hans Christian Andersen, starring Danny Kaye in the title role. Though critics did not hold the screenplay in high regard, they praised Loesser's score and Kaye's performance. In 1974, five years after her husband's death, Loesser's widow, Jo Sullivan, was instrumental in bringing about a stage version of the work, titled Hans Andersen, at the Palladium in London. Though drawing on a book by TOmmy Steele and Beverly Cross, it was based on Goldwyn's movie. Loesser's songs were retained, with additional songs by Marvin Laird. Produced by Harold Fielding (in association with Louis Benjamin), and directed by Freddie Carpenter, the cast included Tommy Steele as Hans Andersen, Colette Gleeson as Jenny Lind, Milo O'Shea as Otto Pedersen, Bob Todd as Meisling and Lila Kaye as Madame Meisling. The musical was revived at the Palladium on 17 Dec 1977, with Tommy Steele as Hans Andersen, Sally Ann Howes as Jenny Lind, Anthony Valentine as Otto Pedersen, and Lila Kaye as Madame Meisling.
Harold Fielding (1916-2003) was one of the foremost producers of stage musicals in Britain from the 1950s to the 1980s. After some success as an orchestral and concert promoter he made his first foray into musical theater in 1958 with a staged version of Rodgers and Hammerstein's Cinderella at the London Coliseum. Among his most successful theater productions were the original Half a Sixpence (1963), Charlie Girl (1965), the London versions of Sweet Charity (1967), and Mame (1969).
Controlled Access
The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this collection. An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated databases.
Harold Fielding, Ltd.; Loesser, Frank, 1910-1969; Ainsworth, Alyn; O'Shea, Milo, 1926-; Valentine, Anthony; Howes, Sally Ann; Pahernik, Albin; Goddard, Willoughby; Hart, Moss, 1904-1961
Container List
- Ainsworth, Alyn.
  - Signed agreement between Harold Fielding Ltd. and Alyn Ainsworth, signed1 Oct 1974, engaging the recipient as Musical Director in the play Hans Andersen at the London Palladium., (1); 2s.
  - Signed agreement between Harold Fielding, Ltd. and Alyn Ainsworth, signed 14 Oct 1974., (2); 1s.
    Agreement is with regard to Ainsworth's schedule and the scheduling of rehearsals.
  - T.L.s. from Dick Katz of M.A.M. Agency to Harold Fielding, 11 Feb 1974., (3); 1s.
- Goddard, Willoughby.
  - Esher Standard Contract for London Theatres between Harold Fielding Ltd. and Willoughby Goddard, signed 25 Oct 1974, engaging the artist to rehearse and play the part of "Colonel Guldberg" in the play Hans Andersen., (1)
    Several related documents are attached to the contract including an addendum dated 25 Oct 1974 and an amendment operative from 6 Mar 1974.
    There is an additional copy of this contract, unsigned.
  - T.L. from M.J. Fielding to Willoughby Goddard, 25 Oct 1974, (2)
  - A.L.s. from Willoughby Goddard to Harold Fielding, 12 Dec 1974., (3)
  - Memorandum from Ian Bevan of Harold Fielding, Ltd., to the company's contract department regarding Goddard's contract, 25 Oct 1974., (4)
  - Signed contract addendum, 20 Jan 1975., (5); Agreement is with regard to scheduling of rehearsals and Goddard's billing. Additional copy of
  - T.L.s. from Joyce Edwards of Representation Joyce Edwards to Ian Bevan at Harold Fielding, Ltd., 18 Feb 1975., (6)
  - T.L.s. from Joyce Edwards of Representation Joyce Edwards to Ian Bevan at Harold Fielding, Ltd., 27 Aug 1975., (7)
  - Note relaying phone message from Mrs. Fielding, 9 Sep 1975., (8)
- Howes, Sally Ann.
  - Esher Standard Contract for London Theatres between Harold Fielding Ltd. and Sally Ann Howes, signed1 July 1977, and engaging the artist to rehearse and play the part of Jenny Lind in the play Hans Andersen., (1)
    An additional copy of the contract is signed on behalf of Howes by the President of All Media Management.
    Related documents are attached to the contract including an addendum dated 19 Nov 1974 and an amendment operative from 6 Mar 1974.
  - Memorandum from Ian Bevan of Harold Fielding, Ltd., to the company's contract department regarding Howes; contract., (2)
  - Note from 'Hilary' relaying phone message from Charles Lubar to unknown recipient, 4 Mar 1978., (3)
  - T.L. from G.M. Keighley at Harold Fielding, Ltd., to Fraser and Dunlop, Ltd., regarding Howes' contract, 22 Mar 1978., (4)
  - T.L. from G.M. Keighley at Harold Fielding, Ltd., to Charles Lubar, 5 Oct 1978., (5)
  - T.L.s., from Charles Lubar to G.M. Keighley, 28 Sep 1978., (6)
- Wells, Tony.
  - T.L.s., from Louis Benjamin, Managing Director of Moss Empire Limited to Harold Fielding, (1)
    Letter is in regard to engaging the services of Tony Wells as Public Relations Officer.
- O'Shea, Milo, 1926-.
  - Esher Standard Contract for London Theatres between Harold Fielding Ltd. and Milo O'Shea, signed 19 Nov 1974, engaging the artist to rehearse and play the part of "Otto Pedersen" in the play Hans Andersen., (1)
    Several related documents are attached to the contract including an addendum dated 19 Nov 1974 and an amendment operative from 6 Mar 1974.
  - T.L. M.J. Fielding for Harold Fielding, Ltd., to Milo O'Shea, 28 Oct 1974., (2)
  - Memorandum from Ian Bevan of Harold Fielding, Ltd., to the company's contract department regarding O'Shea's contract., (3)
  - T.L.s. from Hugh J. Alexander of International Artistes Representation to Ian Bevan at Harold Fielding, Ltd. 28 Nov 1974., (4)
  - T.L.s. from Milo O'Shea to Harold Fielding, Ltd., 10 Dec 1974., (5)
- Pahernik, Albin.
  - Esher Standard Contract for London Theatres between Harold Fielding Ltd. and Albin Pahernik, signed8 Oct 1974, and engaging the artist as a chorister in the play Hans Andersen., (1)
    Related documents are attached to the contract including an addendum dated 8 Oct 1974 and an amendment operative from 6 Mar 1974.
  - A.L.s., from Albin Pahernik to Harold Fielding, Ltd.,, 20 Dec 1974., (2)
  - T.L., from the Director of the production fo Albin Pahernik, 16 Dec 1974., (3)
- Valentine, Anthony.
  - Esher Standard Contract for London Theatres between Harold Fielding Ltd. and Anthony Valentine, signed1 Jul 1977, and engaging the artist to rehearse and play the part of Otto in the play Hans Andersen., (1)
    Several related documents are attached to the contract including an addendum dated 1 Jul 1977 and an amendment operative from 6 Mar 1974.
  - Memorandum from Ian Bevan of Harold Fielding, Ltd., to the company's contract department regarding Valentine's contract., (2)
  - T.L.s. from Anthony Valentine to Harold Fielding, Ltd. 18 Jul 1977., (3)
  - T.L.s. from David White Associates to Ian Bevan of Harold Fielding, Ltd., regarding Valentine's contract, 25 Jul 1977., (4)